# Saurabh Bajaj

# saurabhbsd@gmail.com +91-8000888022

## SUMMARY

Saurabh is an experienced iOS application developer currently working in Pune, India. He likes to come up with simple solutions to difficult problems. Code quality, maintainability and pragmatism are his core programming principles. Being an iOS developer, he gives great attention to the UX and UI of the project.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master in Computer Applications *University of Pune*, Pune

Aug 2013 - Apr 2015

**Bachelor in Computer Applications** 

July 2010 - Apr 2013

University of Pune, Pune

### CERTIFICATIONS

# Diploma in iOS Application Development

June 2014 - Aug 2014

Sourcekode Technologies, Pune

#### CAREER HISTORY

# Senior iOS Developer, Promobi Technologies, Pune

Nov 2015 - Present

- Responsible for the complete product life-cycle from design to implementation and App Store release management.
- Good experience with Swift and Objective C.
- Profiling and optimization to enhance efficiency and performance.
- Timely development and delivery of applications with minimal bugs.

## iOS Developer Intern, Emerson Innovation Center, Pune

Jan 2015 - Aug 2015

• Worked on a Bluetooth based application in Objective-C.

#### SKILLS

Programming Languages: Swift, Objective-C, C++, C, Python(minor experience)

Database: SQLite Version Control: Git

Libraries and Frameworks: Cocoa, AFNetworking, Fabrics (Crashlytics Answers), Firebase, Realm,

Alamofire, CoreBluetooth

Mobile Development: Native iOS Development and Hybrid (minor experience with react native)

*Operating Systems:* macOS, Windows

#### Important links

Github: https://github.com/saurabhbajajcode

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/saurabhbajaj02/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/saurabhbajaj91

## Volunteering Experience

**Volunteer, National level Conference**: Sinhgad Institute of Management and Computer Applications, (Pune)

Feb 2015